// Year 10 Questions Data - Edit this file to add or modify questions
// Questions Data - Edit this file to add or modify questions
const questionsData = [
    { questionNumber: 1, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the symbol for a variable resistor?", answer: "rectangle with diagonal arrow" },
    { questionNumber: 2, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the symbol for an LED?", answer: "circle with triangle and line inside (like a play button) and two small arrows coming off" },
    { questionNumber: 3, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the symbol for a thermistor?", answer: "rectangle with line through (like a hockey stick)" },
    { questionNumber: 4, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the symbol for an open switch?", answer: "two separated circles with a diagonal line from one circle" },
    { questionNumber: 5, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "Which type of circuit has components in different loops?", answer: "Parallel" },
    { questionNumber: 6, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is current?", answer: "Rate of flow of electrons or charge (per second)" },
    { questionNumber: 7, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the unit of current?", answer: "A (Amps)" },
    { questionNumber: 8, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "How do we measure current?", answer: "With an ammeter in series" },
    { questionNumber: 9, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is voltage?", answer: "Difference in electrical energy between two points" },
    { questionNumber: 10, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the unit of voltage?", answer: "V (Volts)" },
    { questionNumber: 11, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "How do we measure voltage?", answer: "With a voltmeter in parallel" },
    { questionNumber: 12, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What happens to current in a series circuit?", answer: "Stays the same everywhere" },
    { questionNumber: 13, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What happens to current in a parallel circuit?", answer: "Splits or shared between loops" },
    { questionNumber: 14, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What happens to voltage in a series circuit?", answer: "Splits or shared between components" },
    { questionNumber: 15, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What happens to voltage in a parallel circuit?", answer: "Stays the same everywhere" },
    { questionNumber: 16, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is a measure of how difficult it is for current to flow?", answer: "Resistance" },
    { questionNumber: 17, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is the unit of resistance?", answer: "Ω (Ohms)" },
    { questionNumber: 18, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What equation links voltage, current and resistance?", answer: "Current = Voltage / Resistance" },
    { questionNumber: 19, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What happens to resistance in series?", answer: "Adds up so total resistance is bigger (R=R1+R2)" },
    { questionNumber: 20, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "HT: What happens to resistance in parallel?", answer: "Total resistance is lower than the smallest resistance (1/R = 1/R1 + 1/R2)" },
    { questionNumber: 21, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "Draw the current voltage graph for a resistor at constant temperature", answer: "straight diagonal line (directly proportional)" },
    { questionNumber: 22, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "Draw the current voltage graph for a filament lamp", answer: "curve (as voltage increases current increases at a decreasing rate)" },
    { questionNumber: 23, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "Draw the current voltage graph for a diode", answer: "flat horizontal line and then sharp rise" },
    { questionNumber: 24, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What is power?", answer: "How much energy is transferred per second" },
    { questionNumber: 25, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What equation links voltage, current and power?", answer: "P = I x V" },
    { questionNumber: 26, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "As light intensity increases what happens to the resistance of an LDR?", answer: "Decreases at a decreasing rate" },
    { questionNumber: 27, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What are LDRs used for in the UK?", answer: "Streetlights" },
    { questionNumber: 28, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "As temperature increases what happens to the resistance of an ntc thermistor?", answer: "Decreases at a decreasing rate" },
    { questionNumber: 29, topic: "Electrical Circuits", question: "What are ntc thermistors used for in the UK?", answer: "Fire alarms" },
    { questionNumber: 30, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What does renewable mean?", answer: "Will not run out and will quickly replenish" },
    { questionNumber: 31, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Name 4 non renewable energy sources", answer: "Coal, Oil, Gas, Nuclear" },
    { questionNumber: 32, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Name 4 renewable energy sources", answer: "Solar, Wind, Hydroelectric, Wave, Biomass, Geothermal, Tidal" },
    { questionNumber: 33, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Which power station uses hot rocks underground to heat water?", answer: "Geothermal" },
    { questionNumber: 34, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What does to commission mean?", answer: "Set up and build" },
    { questionNumber: 35, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give an advantage of Nuclear power stations", answer: "No CO2 produced, very efficient, lots of electricity, small amount of fuel, reliable" },
    { questionNumber: 36, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give a disadvantage of Nuclear power stations", answer: "Produces radioactive waste, expensive to commission and decommission" },
    { questionNumber: 37, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give an advantage of Wind power stations", answer: "No fuel cost, No CO2 produced, Cheap to run" },
    { questionNumber: 38, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give a disadvantage of Wind power stations", answer: "Unreliable, don’t produce much electricity, ugly" },
    { questionNumber: 39, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give an advantage of Hydroelectric power stations", answer: "No fuel cost, No CO2 produced, Quick start up time, lots of electricity" },
    { questionNumber: 40, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give a disadvantage of Hydroelectric power stations", answer: "Destroy habitats, harm wildlife, large area of land needed" },
    { questionNumber: 41, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "How is a Biomass power station \"carbon neutral\"?", answer: "Plants take in carbon dioxide as they grow and release the same carbon dioxide when burned, this recycles the CO2" },
    { questionNumber: 42, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What environmental problem is caused by carbon dioxide?", answer: "Global Warming" },
    { questionNumber: 43, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What environmental problem is caused by sulfur dioxide?", answer: "Acid Rain" },
    { questionNumber: 44, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Which type of power station is the biggest polluter of carbon dioxide?", answer: "Fossil fuels (Coal, Oil, Gas)" },
    { questionNumber: 45, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Which type of power station is the biggest polluter of sulfur dioxide?", answer: "Coal" },
    { questionNumber: 46, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "In a power station what happens after water is heated to make steam?", answer: "Steam turns a turbine" },
    { questionNumber: 47, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What are the 8 different types/forms of energy?", answer: "Heat, Elastic, Chemical, Kinetic, Light, Electrical, Gravitational Potential, Sound" },
    { questionNumber: 48, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give 2 examples of things that have chemical energy", answer: "Battery, Food, Fuel, Petrol" },
    { questionNumber: 49, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give 2 examples of things that have kinetic energy", answer: "Anything that is moving" },
    { questionNumber: 50, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What diagram shows us energy transfers?", answer: "Sankey" },
    { questionNumber: 51, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "On a Sankey diagram which energy goes on the left-hand side?", answer: "Input" },
    { questionNumber: 52, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "On a Sankey diagram which energy goes up/down?", answer: "Wasted Output" },
    { questionNumber: 53, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the law of conservation of energy?", answer: "Energy cannot be created or destroyed; it is transformed from one type to another" },
    { questionNumber: 54, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the unit of energy?", answer: "J (Joules)" },
    { questionNumber: 55, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What does efficient mean?", answer: "Doesn't waste much energy" },
    { questionNumber: 56, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the efficiency equation?", answer: "efficiency = useful output / total input   x 100" },
    { questionNumber: 57, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Why is there a x100 in the efficiency equation?", answer: "To give a percentage" },
    { questionNumber: 58, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the National Grid?", answer: "A system of power stations, cables, pylons and transformers that transport electricity to our homes" },
    { questionNumber: 59, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Why do we have a National Grid connecting all power stations together?", answer: "Reliable (if one power station breaks there is a backup)" },
    { questionNumber: 60, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Which type of power station can be used in an emergency?", answer: "Hydroelectric" },
    { questionNumber: 61, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the role of a step-up transformer?", answer: "Increase voltage, decrease current so less heat is lost" },
    { questionNumber: 62, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What is the role of a step-down transformer?", answer: "Decrease voltage, increase current so it is more safe" },
    { questionNumber: 63, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What ensures the National Grid is efficient?", answer: "Step up transformers" },
    { questionNumber: 64, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Give 2 ways the National Grid monitor the demand for electricity", answer: "Check TV guides, check weather reports, prepare for special events e.g. Olympics" },
    { questionNumber: 65, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What happens if there is a shortage of electricity in the National Grid?", answer: "Power cut" },
    { questionNumber: 66, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "What happens if there is a surplus of electricity in the National Grid?", answer: "Electricity is wasted" },
    { questionNumber: 67, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Why is the demand for electricity lowest between Midnight and 6am?", answer: "Most people are asleep so aren't using much electricity" },
    { questionNumber: 68, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Why is the demand for electricity highest around 7pm?", answer: "People are home from work, cooking dinner, watching TV etc" },
    { questionNumber: 69, topic: "Generating Electricity", question: "Why is the demand for electricity never zero?", answer: "Always something using electricity (Hospitals, Freezers etc)" },
    { questionNumber: 70, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What is density?", answer: "How many particles are in a volume" },
    { questionNumber: 71, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What is the equation to calculate density?", answer: "Density = mass / volume" },
    { questionNumber: 72, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What units is density measured in?", answer: "g/cm3 or kg/m3" },
    { questionNumber: 73, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Which state is the most dense?", answer: "solid" },
    { questionNumber: 74, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How do you find the volume of a regular shaped object (e.g. block of wood)?", answer: "Use a ruler to measure sides then length x width x height" },
    { questionNumber: 75, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How do you find the volume of an irregular shaped object (e.g. rock)?", answer: "Use a measuring cylinder of water or Eureka beaker and measure change in volume when object is added" },
    { questionNumber: 76, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How do you find the mass of a liquid?", answer: "Mass of liquid = mass of cylinder and liquid - mass of empty cylinder" },
    { questionNumber: 77, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Which direction does heat always move?", answer: "From hot to cold" },
    { questionNumber: 78, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What sort of materials does conduction happen in?", answer: "Solids" },
    { questionNumber: 79, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What materials make the best conductors?", answer: "Metals" },
    { questionNumber: 80, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why are metals the good conductors?", answer: "Free electrons can travel and pass heat on faster" },
    { questionNumber: 81, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How do particles pass on heat in conduction?", answer: "Vibrations or collisions with neighbour particles" },
    { questionNumber: 82, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What is an insulator?", answer: "A material that reduces heat loss or transfer" },
    { questionNumber: 83, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What happens to air as it is heated?", answer: "Particles move further apart so it becomes less dense" },
    { questionNumber: 84, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why is the top of an oven hottest?", answer: "Hot air rises as it is less dense" },
    { questionNumber: 85, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How is a convection current set up?", answer: "Hot air rises as it is less dense and cold air sinks as it is more dense" },
    { questionNumber: 86, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How is heat transferred in liquids and gases?", answer: "Convection" },
    { questionNumber: 87, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How does radiation travel?", answer: "As a heat wave" },
    { questionNumber: 88, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How is heat transferred from hot objects e.g. a hob?", answer: "Radiation" },
    { questionNumber: 89, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What colour is best at absorbing heat?", answer: "Black" },
    { questionNumber: 90, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What colour is best at emitting heat?", answer: "Black" },
    { questionNumber: 91, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What colour is best at reflecting heat?", answer: "White/Shiny" },
    { questionNumber: 92, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why does a thermos keep a cup of tea warm?", answer: "Shiny walls reflect heat back into the tea to keep it warm" },
    { questionNumber: 93, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why are houses in Greece painted white?", answer: "To reflect the heat so inside the house stays cool" },
    { questionNumber: 94, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How does heat travel from the Sun to the Earth?", answer: "Radiation (heat wave)" },
    { questionNumber: 95, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "If a black bottle and shiny bottle of cold water are left out in the Sun, why will black heat up quicker?", answer: "Black absorbs heat, shiny reflects heat away" },
    { questionNumber: 96, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why do we need to insulate our homes?", answer: "Reduce heat loss and save money" },
    { questionNumber: 97, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Name 3 types of home insulation", answer: "Double glazing, Cavity wall insulation, Loft insulation, Shiny bubble wrap, Fibre glass, Rock wool, Draught excluders" },
    { questionNumber: 98, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "What is payback time?", answer: "How long it takes to earn the money back for insulation etc" },
    { questionNumber: 99, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "How do you calculate payback time?", answer: "Payback time = cost / savings per year" },
    { questionNumber: 100, topic: "Making Use of Energy", question: "Why does reducing the temperature difference inside and outside the house reduce heat loss?", answer: "The bigger the temperature difference the more heat is transferred" },
    { questionNumber: 101, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What does kWh stand for?", answer: "kilowatt hours" },
    { questionNumber: 102, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is measured in kWh?", answer: "units of electricity" },
    { questionNumber: 103, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "How do you calculate units of electricity used?", answer: "units used (kwh) = power (kW) x time (h)" },
    { questionNumber: 104, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "How do you calculate the cost of electricity used?", answer: "cost = units used x cost per unit" },
    { questionNumber: 105, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is the difference between AC and DC?", answer: "DC current flows in one direction. AC current constantly changes direction" },
    { questionNumber: 106, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Name 2 items that use DC", answer: "Anything with batteries" },
    { questionNumber: 107, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Name 2 items that use AC", answer: "Anything with a plug" },
    { questionNumber: 108, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Is UK mains electricity AC or DC?", answer: "AC" },
    { questionNumber: 109, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is the voltage of UK mains electricity?", answer: "230V (220-240)" },
    { questionNumber: 110, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "On an energy banding sticker which letter and colour are most efficient?", answer: "A Green (A+ or A++)" },
    { questionNumber: 111, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is a fuse?", answer: "Glass tube with thin wire inside" },
    { questionNumber: 112, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "How does a fuse protect from fires?", answer: "Fuse wire melts when current exceeds limit and breaks the circuit" },
    { questionNumber: 113, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What are the standard UK fuse sizes?", answer: "3A, 5A, 13A" },
    { questionNumber: 114, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What would happen if an 11A appliance is fitted with a 5A fuse?", answer: "The appliance won't work as the fuse will melt before the current is high enough to turn it on" },
    { questionNumber: 115, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What would happen if an 2A appliance is fitted with a 5A fuse?", answer: "There could be a fire because the current allowed before the fuse melts is too high" },
    { questionNumber: 116, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Give a disadvantage of fitting every appliance with a fuse", answer: "It needs to be replaced if it blows" },
    { questionNumber: 117, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What does MCB stand for?", answer: "Miniature Circuit Breaker" },
    { questionNumber: 118, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Why are MCBs better than fuses?", answer: "Can be reset, work much faster" },
    { questionNumber: 119, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What does RCCB stand for?", answer: "Residual Current Circuit Breaker" },
    { questionNumber: 120, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Which wires do RCCBs measure the current in?", answer: "Live and Neutral" },
    { questionNumber: 121, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What do RCCBs protect from?", answer: "Electric shock (electrocution)" },
    { questionNumber: 122, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What type of devices use RCCBs?", answer: "Lawnmowers and power tools" },
    { questionNumber: 123, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is the main parallel circuit used in homes called?", answer: "Ring main" },
    { questionNumber: 124, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What are the three wires in a domestic UK circuit?", answer: "Live, Earth and Neutral" },
    { questionNumber: 125, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Which wire are fuses and switches connect to?", answer: "Live" },
    { questionNumber: 126, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "What is the purpose of the Earth wire?", answer: "Safely carry current to ground if there is a fault" },
    { questionNumber: 127, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Give 2 advantages of the ring main", answer: "Thinner cables, Cables carry less current, Sockets can be placed anywhere, Each socket has same voltage, Sockets can be operated independently" },
    { questionNumber: 128, topic: "Domestic Electricity", question: "Where are the mains switch and fuses/MCBs found in the house?", answer: "Consumer unit" },
    { questionNumber: 129, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the amplitude of a wave?", answer: "Maximum displacement (half height)" },
    { questionNumber: 130, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the wavelength of a wave?", answer: "Length of one complete wave (e.g. peak to peak)" },
    { questionNumber: 131, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the frequency of a wave?", answer: "The number of waves per second" },
    { questionNumber: 132, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the time period of a wave?", answer: "The time it takes for one complete wave" },
    { questionNumber: 133, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the unit for wavelength?", answer: "m (metres)" },
    { questionNumber: 134, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the unit for frequency?", answer: "Hz (hertz)" },
    { questionNumber: 135, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the wave equation?", answer: "Wave speed = wavelength x frequency" },
    { questionNumber: 136, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the symbol used to indicate wavelength?", answer: "λ (lambda)" },
    { questionNumber: 137, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is a transverse wave?", answer: "A wave with oscillations (vibrations) at right angles to the direction of motion (propagation)" },
    { questionNumber: 138, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is a longitudinal wave?", answer: "A wave with oscillations (vibrations) in the same direction as motion (propagation)" },
    { questionNumber: 139, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Give an example of a transverse wave", answer: "Water waves, light, EM spectrum" },
    { questionNumber: 140, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Give an example of a longitudinal wave", answer: "Sound wave, pressure wave" },
    { questionNumber: 141, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the law of reflection?", answer: "angle of incidence = angle of reflection" },
    { questionNumber: 142, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What is the bending of light called?", answer: "refraction" },
    { questionNumber: 143, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Why does light bend when it enters a glass block?", answer: "slows down as it enters a more dense material" },
    { questionNumber: 144, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Write the EM spectrum in order from longest to shortest wavelength", answer: "Radio, Microwave, Infrared, Visible, Uv, Xray, Gamma" },
    { questionNumber: 145, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What do all EM waves have in common?", answer: "Travel at the same speed, all transverse waves" },
    { questionNumber: 146, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Which EM wave as the longest wavelength/lowest frequency?", answer: "Radio" },
    { questionNumber: 147, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Which EM wave as the shortest wavelength/highest frequency?", answer: "Gamma" },
    { questionNumber: 148, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What are some uses and dangers of Gamma rays?", answer: "Used to treat cancer, Ionising" },
    { questionNumber: 149, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What does ionising mean?", answer: "Removes electrons, damages DNA and causes cancer" },
    { questionNumber: 150, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What type of EM waves do satellites use?", answer: "Microwaves" },
    { questionNumber: 151, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "What are some disadvantages of satellites?", answer: "Time delay, Can be affected by weather" },
    { questionNumber: 152, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Describe the orbit of a Geosynchronous satellite", answer: "orbits the Earth every 24 hours, however only returns to exactly the same place once every 24 hours" },
    { questionNumber: 153, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Describe the orbit of a Geostationary satellite", answer: "stays above a fixed point of the Earth and takes 24 hours to orbit" },
    { questionNumber: 154, topic: "Features of Waves", question: "Which type of satellite are used for satellite TV and communications?", answer: "Geostationary" },
    { questionNumber: 155, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What does TIR stand for?", answer: "Total Internal Reflection" },
    { questionNumber: 156, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What are the two conditions for TIR?", answer: "angle of incidence greater than critical angle and travelling in more dense material" },
    { questionNumber: 157, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What happens if angle of incidence is smaller than critical angle?", answer: "Refraction" },
    { questionNumber: 158, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What happens if angle of incidence is equal to critical angle?", answer: "Travel along boundary (maximum refraction)" },
    { questionNumber: 159, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What happens if angle of incidence is larger than critical angle?", answer: "Total Internal Reflection" },
    { questionNumber: 160, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "Give 2 uses of optical fibres", answer: "Endoscopes, Communications, TV, Internet, Lights" },
    { questionNumber: 161, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What is an optical fibre made of?", answer: "Thin rod of glass" },
    { questionNumber: 162, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What type of EM waves do optical fibres use for communications?", answer: "Infrared" },
    { questionNumber: 163, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "Why are optical fibres better than satellites for communication?", answer: "Less time delay, not affected by weather, send more data, easier to repair, no interference" },
    { questionNumber: 164, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What type of EM waves are used in a CT (CAT) Scan?", answer: "X-rays" },
    { questionNumber: 165, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "How is a CT (CAT) Scan different to an X-ray?", answer: "Multiple x-rays taken around the body to form a 3D image" },
    { questionNumber: 166, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "Why is a CT (CAT) Scan more dangerous than a single X-ray?", answer: "Multiple x-rays taken around the body so more ionising radiation means higher risk of cancer" },
    { questionNumber: 167, topic: "Total Internal Reflection", question: "What type of EM waves are used in an endoscope?", answer: "Visible light" },
    { questionNumber: 168, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Where do earthquakes usually occur?", answer: "Along tectonic plate boundaries" },
    { questionNumber: 169, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Describe the motion of tectonic plates that causes an earthquake", answer: "Stress builds up then plates slip past each other releasing energy" },
    { questionNumber: 170, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What does P wave stand for?", answer: "Primary wave" },
    { questionNumber: 171, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What type of wave is a P wave?", answer: "Longitudinal" },
    { questionNumber: 172, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What materials can a P wave travel through?", answer: "Liquids and Solids" },
    { questionNumber: 173, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What does S wave stand for?", answer: "Secondary wave" },
    { questionNumber: 174, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What type of wave is an S wave?", answer: "Transverse" },
    { questionNumber: 175, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What materials can an S wave travel through?", answer: "Only solids" },
    { questionNumber: 176, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Which type of seismic wave causes the most damage to buildings?", answer: "Surface waves" },
    { questionNumber: 177, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Which type of seismic wave travels at the fastest speed?", answer: "Primary wave" },
    { questionNumber: 178, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Name the 4 layers of the Earth in order", answer: "Crust, Mantle, Outer Core, Inner Core" },
    { questionNumber: 179, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Which layers of the Earth are solid?", answer: "Crust, Mantle and Inner core" },
    { questionNumber: 180, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Which layers of the Earth are liquid?", answer: "Outer core" },
    { questionNumber: 181, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "Which type of waves can travel through the core?", answer: "Primary wave" },
    { questionNumber: 182, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What happens when a P wave reaches a boundary of a new layer inside the Earth?", answer: "Changes speed and refracts" },
    { questionNumber: 183, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What happens when an S wave reaches the boundary of the core?", answer: "It reflects off" },
    { questionNumber: 184, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What is the S wave shadow zone?", answer: "Area where no S waves are detected" },
    { questionNumber: 185, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What does the S wave shadow zone tell us about the Earth?", answer: "It has a liquid core and the size of the core" },
    { questionNumber: 186, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What piece of equipment is used to record and monitor earthquakes?", answer: "Seismogram (seismometer)" },
    { questionNumber: 187, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What name is given to the gap between when P and S waves arrive?", answer: "Lag time" },
    { questionNumber: 188, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "If seismogram A shows a bigger lag time than seismogram B what does this mean?", answer: "The epicentre of the earthquake is closer to B than A" },
    { questionNumber: 189, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "How many seismograms are needed to locate an epicentre?", answer: "3" },
    { questionNumber: 190, topic: "Seismic Waves", question: "What is the name of the process using multiple seismograms to locate an epicentre?", answer: "Triangulation" },
    { questionNumber: 191, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is the equation to calculate pressure?", answer: "Pressure = Force / Area" },
    { questionNumber: 192, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What units are used for pressure?", answer: "N/m2  or Pa   or N/cm2" },
    { questionNumber: 193, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "Which produces a higher pressure snow boots or high heels? Why?", answer: "High heels have a bigger pressure as they have a smaller surface area" },
    { questionNumber: 194, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What name is given to the theory that describe gas as particles constantly moving in random directions?", answer: "Kinetic theory" },
    { questionNumber: 195, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What causes gas pressure?", answer: "Particles collide with surface of an object and exert a force which creates a pressure" },
    { questionNumber: 196, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "Give 2 assumptions of kinetic theory", answer: "Particles constantly move, travel in random directions, travel in straight lines, don't lose energy in collisions" },
    { questionNumber: 197, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What happens to pressure when volume increases?", answer: "Pressure decreases at a decreasing rate because there is more room so less collisions" },
    { questionNumber: 198, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What happens to pressure when temperature increases?", answer: "Pressure increases (directly proportional) because more energy and more collisions" },
    { questionNumber: 199, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What happens to volume when temperature increases?", answer: "Volume increases (directly proportional) because energy increases so particles move further apart" },
    { questionNumber: 200, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What name is given to the temperature where particles have no energy and exert no pressure?", answer: "Absolute zero" },
    { questionNumber: 201, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What temperature is absolute zero?", answer: "0 kelvin = -273 degrees celsius" },
    { questionNumber: 202, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is 25deg celsius in kelvin?", answer: "298K" },
    { questionNumber: 203, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is specific heat capacity?", answer: "Amount of heat energy needed to increase the temperature of 1kg by 1degree" },
    { questionNumber: 204, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is the specific heat capacity equation?", answer: "Q = m x c x Δϴ" },
    { questionNumber: 205, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What symbol is used to represent heat energy?", answer: "Q" },
    { questionNumber: 206, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What symbol is used to represent temperature?", answer: "ϴ" },
    { questionNumber: 207, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What does Δ represent?", answer: "change in" },
    { questionNumber: 208, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is specific latent heat of fusion?", answer: "Amount of heat energy needed to change 1kg from solid to liquid" },
    { questionNumber: 209, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is specific latent heat of vaporisation?", answer: "Amount of heat energy needed to change 1kg from liquid to vapour (gas)" },
    { questionNumber: 210, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "What is the specific latent heat equation?", answer: "Q = m x L" },
    { questionNumber: 211, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "Why does the temperature not increase when a solid is melting?", answer: "Energy is used to break the bonds instead of increasing temperature" },
    { questionNumber: 212, topic: "Kinetic Theory", question: "Why is SLH of fusion less than SLH vaporisation?", answer: "More bonds to break going from liquid to gas then from solid to liquid" },
    { questionNumber: 213, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What is a magnetic field?", answer: "Region where magnetic materials feel a force" },
    { questionNumber: 214, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Draw the magnetic field for a bar magnet", answer: "Loops from N to S, lots of lines at the ends of the magnet" },
    { questionNumber: 215, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Describe the magnetic field of a current carrying wire", answer: "circles around the wire getting further apart" },
    { questionNumber: 216, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "If a current carrying wire is held vertically with current flowing downwards what direction would the magnetic field be?", answer: "clockwise" },
    { questionNumber: 217, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Which rule do you use to find the magnetic field direction for a current carrying wire?", answer: "Right hand grip rule" },
    { questionNumber: 218, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What is a solenoid?", answer: "Coil of wire" },
    { questionNumber: 219, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What 3 things do magnetic field lines show?", answer: "Shape, direction and strength of magnetic field" },
    { questionNumber: 220, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Where is the magnetic field strongest on a bar magnet?", answer: "At the poles as there are more field lines close together" },
    { questionNumber: 221, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Which direction do magnetic field lines travel on a bar magnet?", answer: "North --> South" },
    { questionNumber: 222, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Which rule do you use to find the movement of a wire in a motor?", answer: "Fleming's Left-Hand Rule" },
    { questionNumber: 223, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What does each finger represent in Fleming's Left-Hand Rule?", answer: "Thumb = movement (force) , First finger = magnetic field, Second finger = current" },
    { questionNumber: 224, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What names is given to the effect where a current carrying wire in a magnetic field experiences a force?", answer: "Motor effect" },
    { questionNumber: 225, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "In the equation F = B x I x L what does B represent?", answer: "Magnetic field strength" },
    { questionNumber: 226, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "How can you increase the size of the force on a wire in a motor?", answer: "Increase current, Increase magnetic field strength, Increase number of turns (length of wire)" },
    { questionNumber: 227, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Why do motors need to use a split ring commutator?", answer: "To reverse the current every half turn so motor continually spins in one direction" },
    { questionNumber: 228, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What process occurs when a wire moves through a magnetic field producing a current?", answer: "Electromagnetic Induction" },
    { questionNumber: 229, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "If a wire moves the opposite way through a magnetic field what happens to the current?", answer: "Reverses direction" },
    { questionNumber: 230, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "How can you increase the current induced from a generator?", answer: "Move wire (or magnet) faster, Add more turns to wire, Increase magnetic field strength" },
    { questionNumber: 231, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Which rule do you use to find the direction of current in a generator?", answer: "Fleming's Right Hand Rule" },
    { questionNumber: 232, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What does each finger represent in Fleming's Right Hand Rule?", answer: "Thumb = movement (force) , First finger = magnetic field, Second finger = current" },
    { questionNumber: 233, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Why do generators produce AC electricity?", answer: "Current that is induced reverses direction every half turn" },
    { questionNumber: 234, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "Why so transformers have an iron core?", answer: "To pass on the alternating magnetic field from primary to secondary coil" },
    { questionNumber: 235, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "How is an alternating current set up in the secondary coil of a transformer?", answer: "Alternating magnetic field induces an alternating voltage and current" },
    { questionNumber: 236, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What is the transformer equation?", answer: "V1/V2 = N1/N2" },
    { questionNumber: 237, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What assumption is made in the transformer equation?", answer: "100%" },
    { questionNumber: 238, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "N1=2000  V1=240V   V2=4.8V  how many turns are on the secondary coil?", answer: "40 turns" },
    { questionNumber: 239, topic: "Electromagnetism", question: "What unit is magnetic field strength measured in?", answer: "T (Tesla)" }
];
